阿者言无 鼻者名间 为无时间
Avici Hell. Also known as Continuous Hell.
为无空间 为无量受业报之界
Uninterrupted Time. Unlimited Space. Boundless suffering for the fallen souls.
无时间
Uninterrupted Time
(时间)
(Time)
我还记得我第一次抓那个犯人
I still remember my first arrest.
(1991年)
(1991)
那天是八零年十二月十二日
It was December 12, 1980.
我跟一个师兄在河内道巡逻
My partner and I were patrolling Hanoi Road.
那么收到通知 说新世界有案件发生
Shit was going down at New World Centre.
我们俩立刻赶去
We rushed over.
到了现场 看见几十个人挥舞刀棍正在械斗
A gang fight was taking place.
有十几个已经倒在地上
About 15 or so were already down.
地上有好多血
Lots of blood on the ground.
我更看见一只握了刀的断手
Plus a severed hand, still holding a knife.
师兄叫我开枪
My partner told me to draw my weapon.
当时我是个新丁 师兄说什么我就做什么 是吧!
I was a rookie so I did what he told me to.
谁知道我还没来得及打开枪套呢
But before I could open the holster,
师兄已经"扑通" 跌倒在我面前了
My partner already dropped
我看见那小子拿根铁管插进师兄的肚子里
This kid stabbed a pipe into his belly
那血呢 就不停从那里面流出来
Blood gushed out of the sawed-off opening
当时我的脑袋一片空白
I didn't know what to think.
只知道把六颗子弹
I simply emptied all six of my bullets
一下子全打在那小子的身上
straight into that kid.
后来那小子判了多少年我记的不大清楚
I don't remember how many years he got.
两年前 我又遇上那小子了
But when I saw him again two years ago,
穿的衣着光鲜 跟一伙人在富豪喝酒
he was boozing in a club, looking sharp.
跟着一块的那几个人呢 就是倪坤的手下
His buddies were all Kwun's goons!
杀人放火金腰带 修桥补路无尸骸
Evil prevails. Only the good die young.
那个师兄长什么样子我已经很模糊了
I can barely recall my partner's face now.
我很后悔
I regret...
那六枪没打在那小子的头上
the six bullets weren't put into that kid's skull.
世界不应该是这样
The world shouldn't be like this.
做人不应该是这样 琛
That's not the way it should be, Sam.
你来尖沙嘴多久?
How long have you been around Tsim Sha Tsui?
快两年了吧
Almost two years now.
你知不知道这两年来我为什么没有抓你?
Do you know why I haven't messed with you?
我长得帅吧
'Cause I'm handsome.
可能是吧
Maybe so.
因为我觉得你还像个人
'Cause I think you 're a decent guy.
如果尖沙嘴是你的地头 我就清闲多了
I'd rather you be in charge in Tsim Sha Tsui.
算了吧
Forget about it.
六颗子弹都没打死那小子
You couldn't waste the kid even with six bullets.
你也算是个好人 对吧?
That makes you a decent guy, too. Right?
别笑话我了 这个好人我宁愿不做
Let me put it this way. I'd rather not be one.
我这条命 是坤哥给我的
Kwun gave me everything, even my life.
我要是帮你对付他 我还算是个人吗?
If I turned against him
你也会看不起我吧 对不对?
I'd be despicable even in your eyes. Right?
- 早就料到你是这样 - 本来就是嘛
- I knew you 'd say that. - Yeah!
不过为倪家做事呢 不能只讲义气
Chivalry means little to the Ngai's Family
师傅常常告诫我
The Master often says...
因果报应总有时
"Retribution knows its time."
我也害怕最后几年不能和你吃饭
Who knows how you and I will end up?
开工了
Time to work.
还早呢 这么拼命干什么?
This early? What's the rush?
我不吃 小的也要吃啊
I've got to eat. So do my boys.
全都拿走吧 还有这个
Take the whole box.
不要了 留给你吧
That's okay. Keep it.
不用了 走吧
Don't worry about it. Just go.
走了
Gotta go.
要不要带你走后门?
Want to use the back door?
条例没规定不许跟警察做朋友吧
Ain't no rules against schmoozing with cops.
走正门行了 习惯了
The front door's fine. Got used to it.
宝勒巷
Prat Avenue!
宝勒巷 劳驾
Prat Avenue, please.
我找坤叔
Is Uncle Kwun in?
坤叔 有人找你
Uncle Kwun! Someone's looking for you .
我走了 Mary姐
Bye, Mary.
这部美国古董机
They say this American antique's got
有人说它高音甜 中音准 低音劲什么的
a sweet high, crisp middle, and strong bass.
真是瞎扯蛋
Bullshit!
要十八万呢
180 grand!
香港有多少人买得起?
Who can afford it in Hong Kong?
坐
Sit.
玩得起的人有一万多
Only around ten thousand people can afford it
琛哥叫你去警察那边做卧底
Sam asked you to be a mole in the force.
你要是不喜欢 我去跟他说一声
If you don't like it, I can talk to him.
怎么说你也是我的人
You're my boy after all
没事
It's fine with me.
真的没事?
Sure?
真的
Positive.
帮我把那个袋子拿过来
Hand me that bag.
玛莉姐
Mary.
我看你最近无精打采的 还以为你不想去呢
I thought you'd been dreading it
这几天风声紧 回屯门蹲一段时间吧
Hide in Tuen Mun till things quiet down.
炼好身体等警察学校开学
Stay fit for the Academy's new term.
给你这笔钱 省着点用
The money I gave you, spend wisely.
喜欢这首歌?
You like the song?
是啊
Yeah.
送给你
It's yours.
但是用别的机子放 效果差很远
It won't sound as good on another player.
以后赚到钱 我给你找一部好的
Someday I'll pick out a good one for you
怎么 不喜欢?
What? Don't like it?
不是
Not at all.
这表 琛哥送给你的?
Sam gave you this watch, didn't he?
不关你事
None of your business.
今天晚上的事
Only you and I...
只有你和我知道
...know about tonight.
我不想琛哥知道
I don't want Sam to know.
为什么?
Why's that?
做女人很简单
Women are simple.
只要男人好 我做什么都行
A man treats me well, I'd do anything.
你先回去吧 我今天晚上会很忙
Now go home. I'm very busy tonight.
没什么的 出来混 不是你扁我就是我扁你
It's either you or me.
师傅说我今天有血光之灾 我知道
The boss predicted I would get hurt today.
那又怎么样?表叔看得起我 老是问我
The Mainlander kept asking...
强哥 今天有没有奔驰啊?
"Got a Mercedes today, Keung?"
我当然说有了 所以就出事了
I said, "Of course." And here I am!
要不然 我用得着对着你?
Otherwise, I wouldn't be here with you .
我啊 早就在中国城搂着妹妹 享受大餐了
Mainland girls in arms.
还用说?
That's for sure!
哎 来根烟抽抽啊
Hey, got a cigarette?
我不抽烟的
I don't smoke.
我看算了吧 我的车也没事
Let's forget about it. My car's fine.
就是嘛 事主都说没事了
See! She says it's all good
没什么的 你看看你
Dressed all dandy.
穿的那么斯文 当然不想多事了
Don't want any trouble, do you?
你看我 给你打的
Look at me. All beaten up by you.
你说 到了法庭法官信谁?你自己想想
Who do you think the judge would believe?
还有啊 你们不去尖东吗?
I bet you guys never go to Tsim Sha Tsui East, huh?
你知道我是谁呀?我是傻强
Know who I am? I'm Keung!
韩琛的头马 迪路的头马
Sam's top dog. Del Piero's boy.
怎么样?当然见你一次打你一次
I'll kick your ass every time I see you.
还用说?
And you can count on that.
诶
Hey,you .
警官 我看叫救护车吧
How about calling an ambulance, sir?
你看 流血了都
Look at all the blood!
叫他们多准备500毫升O型血 很难找的
Have them bring 500 cc Type O. It's rare!
O什么O?
Shut up!
跟我回警局再慢慢解释
Wait till we're back to the station
- 带走! - 喂 为什么要我去警局?
- Take him. - Why do I have to go to the station?
喂 现在车又没丢 干么要我上警局?
I only stole a piece of junk, sir. What've I done to deserve the OCTB?
- 闭嘴吧!还说! - 喂!跟你们回去 还不是让你们扁?
- Just shut up! - Does that deserve an OCTB beating?
知不知道你只是个学警?
Don't you know you're just a cadet?
还说今年想拿全班第一呢?
And you are expected to get a medal this year?
别让叶长官知道
Don't ever let Yip know about this!
叶长官 生日快乐
Happy birthday, Officer Yip.
什么快乐?
What's there to be happy about?
在警校蹲了十年 见树比见人还多
Ten years in the Academy. A rustic hell.
你都能把我弄出去
You even managed to get me out.
你的案子已经隔了那么长时间
Your case is now ancient history.
想一想 把自己也申调出去算了
Get yourself out.
虽然现在由华人担任处长
So what if the Commissioner is Chinese now?
但要等老外都走了 还要六年
Still six more years till the hand-over.
那时候我四十八了
I'll be 48 by then.
不如在学校 多教几个好警察
Might as well train a few good cops here.
九七后看你们的了
The world is yours after 1997!
27149 干杯...
27149! Cheers!
阿仁
Yan.
响了一整天了
Been beeping the whole day,
怎么不回电话?
How come you don't call back?
女朋友?
Girlfriend?
干杯 长官 干杯...
Cheers, sir!  Cheers!
滚啊
Just leave me alone!
不关我的事 我也不想知道
It's none of my business. I don't want to know a thing.
滚!滚啊!
Go! Leave me alone!
罗继
Law.
你干什么?
What do you want?
我爸爸刚去世
My father just passed way.
他生前曾经吩咐过
It was his wish to inform his children...
如果他出事的话 就要通知所有的子女
...when something bad happened to him.
不好意思 打扰了
Sorry to have bothered you!
黑鬼 看什么电视 先吃饭吧
Stop watching TV! Eatfirst, Negro!
坤叔走了 看电视台有什么消息
I wonder what they have on Kwun's death.
文拯 这事你干的?
Did you do it, Ching?
我嘴巴大 要是我干的
I've got a big mouth. Had I done it...
早就通天啦
...you would've heard about it!
你问问国华 甘地
Ask Wah and Gandhi.
哎 那就糟了 坤叔死的时候
When Kwun died, I was in Macau.
我正在澳门谈生意
Everybody knows!
这回 他的子女一定算在我头上
But I bet his kids think I did it.
- 我甘地怕什么呀! - 就是
- I ain't scared of nothing - Right.
大儿子当医生 小儿子游手好闲
The eldest son's a doctor. The youngest a brat.
女儿嫁人了
The daughter's been married for ages.
只剩下二儿子看着他的生意
Only the middle son's running the show.
如果他们太过份 我随时收拾他们
If they go too far, I'll show them!
没保护好坤叔 是我们不好
We failed to protect Kwun. It's ourfault!
三叔 算了
That's enough, Uncle John.
爸爸常说
Dad used to say...
"出来跑 迟早要还的"
"What goes around comes around."
他现在才出事 算是赚了
It came later than expected already.
你们谁能猜到 国华 文拯...
Wah, Ching, Negro and Gandhi.
黑鬼 甘地他们四个 现在想什么?
Guess what those four are thinking?
麻烦你们 谢谢
Thank you . Thank you all.
姐 妈妈怎么样?没事吧?
How's mom doing, sis?
没事 一早睡着了
She's fine. Been sleeping.
她吩咐 买几包香烟送去殓房给爸爸
She wants us to bring some cigs to the morgue for Dad.
我去买
I'll go get them.
B组负责把守德诚街两边的街口
B Team, watch Tak Shing Street.
C组呢 把守财务公司那幢大厦
C Team, watch the Austin Road exit...
在柯士甸道这边的出入口
...of thatfinancial building
这幢大厦有两个出入口
It has two exits
一个在德诚街 一个在柯...
One on Tak Shing Street. One on Austin...
对不起
Sorry.
喂?
Hello?
倪坤死了这么大的事 你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you call me that Kwun was dead?
一出事我就通知所有人了 大哥
I called everybody the minute it happened!
倪坤一死 下面的肯定坐不住
Kwun's boys can't sit still for sure
今晚尖沙嘴呀 准有事发生
Shit will hit the fan in Tsim Sha Tsui tonight.
你不知道 今天十四号
It's the 14th already. You know that?
今天十四号 大家都要向倪家交钱
The 14th. Time to pay the Ngai Family
这里我最小
I'm the junior partner here.
不好听的话我来说
So let me be the jackass.
这个月起 我不再交钱给坤叔啦
I'm not paying the Ngai's anymore
三位大哥的意思呢?
What do you three think?
来 喝酒
Cheers.
黄警官
Inspector Wong.
怎么样?
What's up?
你手下在国华楼下干什么呢?
What are your men doing outside Wah's building?
啊 今天先不谈啊
Not a good time to chitchat.
不要耍我啊!
Are you up to something?
行... 改天再说啊
Fine, fine. Next time.
哇 这么热闹?
What's the occasion?
来... 给我个位子
Come on. Where's my seat?
你要是来吃饭 我们会很高兴
Only if you 're here for the food. Then we're cool.
其它的事 过了今晚再说
All other business will have to wait.
吃东西呀!吃吧
The food. It's all about the food.
今天晚上肯定不简单
Tonight's gonna be the shit.
没办法 等他们四个老大办完事
Let the Big Four do their things
我们再收拾残局吧
We'll deal with the aftermath.
这仗一打
Don't let them start fighting
不知道死多少人
or you'll see bodies.
怎么?不满意啊?
What? You don't dig it?
照旧 抽牌决定
You know the rule. Pick a card.
好呀 我们比大
Okay. Higher points win
来呀
Come on!
没话好说啦!还找我干什么?
There's nothing left to talk about. What do you want from me?
怎么样 阿孝?
What's up, Hau?
国华
Wah.
没什么
Nothing much.
我知道你最近在澳门谈赌场的生意
Heard you're planning a casino in Macau.
政府方面我已经谈妥了
I've got the authorities in my pocket.
看你有没有兴趣一起搞
How about a joint venture?
坤叔死了
Uncle Kwun's dead.
我什么兴趣都没有
I'm not in the mood.
那倒是
I see.
你到澳门不只是谈生意
The Macau trip wasn't all business.
还跟甘地的老婆玩得挺开心
I know you had fun with Gandhi's wife.
不好意思 我澳门的赌场不能放手
Sorry, but I can't let go of my casino in Macau.
我先走了
Gotta go.
韩琛那帮人在搞什么?
What are Sam's people doing?
我知道国华已经交钱了
I know Wah paid up.
你别把话岔开
Don't change the subject.
告诉我不知道的事 好不好?
Tell me something I don't know.
好了 等你搞清楚再打给我
Call me when you get your shit straight!
阿孝上去不到十分钟就搞定了国华
Hau took care of Wah in ten minutes.
我看今晚那四个老大很难搞定他
The Big Four are having a tough time.
我的线人说他拿了一百万毒品出来
Hau took out a million's worth of coke.
干什么?
What?
黑社会封路啊?
Mafia road block or what?
倪先生 国华为何要交钱 我不知道
I don't know why Wah paid up, Hau.
总之 我是没得商量
But I ain't gonna negotiate.
我没打算跟你商量
I don't plan to negotiate with you, either.
你叫黑鬼听
Pass the phone to Negro.
黑鬼
Hey, Negro.
我也不晓得他为什么在我地盘打电话给你
Don't know why he calls you from my hood.
怎么样 阿孝?
What's up, Hau?
甘地说的就等于是我说的
I'm with Gandhi all the way.
他不交 我也不交了
He's not paying, neitherwill I!
不要紧 听说最近你跟甘地走得挺近
Heard you and Gandhi have been tight.
还一起运了一批海洛因 但是被人劫走了
The heroin you two smuggled got robbed.
每人损失了几百万 对吧?
Lost several millions each, right?
幸好 我在你的仓里捡回来
Luckily I found the stuff in your warehouse.
要不要我现在交给甘地的小弟?
Want me to hand it back to Gandhi now?
喂 他说什么呀?
What's he talking about?
尖沙嘴五帮人
Among the Tsim Sha Tsui Big Fives...
国华 黑鬼都交钱了
Wah and Negro paid up.
加上琛哥 三比二
Counting Sam, that's 3 to 2.
这儿我最小 不交不行
I'm the junior partner here. Gotta pay!
二位 告辞
See ya!
别想那么多了 干杯
Don't think too much. Cheers!
给我把钱交了
Pay my share for me.
黄警官 倪先生让我告诉你 他吃宵夜去了
Mr. Ngai went to get a quick bite, Inspector Wong.
倪先生 这么晚才吃饭?
A bit late for chowing down, don't you think?
这么多年来 爸爸习惯了来这儿吃宵夜
My dad always came here after work.
我今晚办完事 照例来光顾一下
I have to keep up the ritual.
怎么样 有没有兴趣?一起
Want to join us?
看来这位子是你来坐了 辛苦了
It's your seat from now on. Must be tough.
哪儿的话
Not at all.
你们今晚劳师动众
You guys worked all night for nothing.
但是一无收获 不是更辛苦?
Now that's tough.
阿孝 你今天晚上表现真不错
Well done, Hau .
我希望你一直这样
Hope you can keep it up.
我不想看到以后有什么事发生 走
Don't let it turn into a tragedy. Let's go.
你不想什么?
What did you say?
我们想开香槟庆祝
We want to celebrate.
倪坤死了
Kwun's dead.
我们想开香槟庆祝
Time to pop the champagne.
要不要我给开一瓶啊?
Want me to pop one for you?
干什么?
What?
想干警察?
Want to mess with cops?
哎!两位警官
Officers!
今天倪家已经少了个人
The Ngai's are in mourning,
还想怎么样?
What more do you want?
走吧 走
Let's go. Let's go.
琛哥
Sam.
谢谢
Thanks.
爸爸以前开小赌档
Dad used to operate street gambling here.
从几毛钱小生意
Started out as...
做到现在
a nickel-and-dime business.
整个尖沙嘴没有人不认识他
Now who doesn't know his name in Tsim Sha Tsui?
他常说出来跑...
He often said...
迟早要还
"What goes around comes around."
想不到今天...
And now he's...
我会永远记住今天
I'll always remember this day.
喂
Hello?
老婆 没事了 要不要宵夜?
Hi. honey. It's all good. Want some snacks?
没事就好 我回家等你
Good to hear that. Just come home.
27149.
当警察的一定要身家清白
An officer has to have a clean background.
虽然你跟母姓 多年来跟倪家没来往
Though you cut your ties with the Ngai's and changed your last name...
但你和倪永孝到底是同一个父亲
...you still share the same father with Hau
已经违反了虚报个人背景的校规
That means you lied on your application.
我一定要开除你
I have to let you go.
但你走之前
But before you leave...
你先见一见刚才穿错袜子的那个人
...go see "Mr. Wrong Socks" first
还想不想当警察?
Still want to be a cop?
我还可以吗?
Can I still?
只要你给我一个好的理由
Only if you can give me a good reason.
我想做好人
I want to be a righteous person.
要当警察
If you want to be a cop...
除了帮我 你没别的选择
...then lend me a hand. Simple as that
你选我 是因为我是阿孝的弟弟?
You picked me 'cause I'm Hau 's brother, right?
当有需要的时候 你会不会亲手捉他?
When the time comes, will you arrest him yourself?
那我怎么开始?
How do I start?
别吵 安静点
Shut up, Keep quiet
你不认识我 在这儿
- You don't know me. - Over here!
揍他!
Get him!
揍他
Get him! Get him!
蹲下
Brace
哎 长官 怎么样 赛果怎么样啊?
What's the score, Officer?
别吵
Shut up.
哎你看 傻强啊!
Any casualties?
还好吗?
You okay?
挺得住吗?
Hanging in there?
怎么样?
What's wrong?
打得你很疼啊?
Does it still hurt?
我老爸今天死了
My dad passed away today.
他是最疼我的
He was so good to me.
我去求长官...
I asked the officer...
问他能不能让我出去拜他
if I could go to his funeral.
长官就对我说...
The officer said...
他说 "你知不知道什么叫坐牢?
"Know what it means to be a prisoner?
"坐牢就是 就算你老爸死了
"It means you're not allowed
"也不能让你出去拜的
"even to attend your father's funeral.
你明不明白?"
Don't you know that?"
走吧
Get out of here!
哎 别这样 别哭了
Come on. Stop that
(时间)
(Time)
(1995年)
(Year: 1995)
你有病?
Are you nuts?
你派阿仁去做卧底
You sent Yan to be a mole?
你知不知道阿孝是他亲哥哥?
Don't you know Hau's his half-brother?
那又怎么样?
So what?
把他资料给我
Bring me his file!
你不是升了官就给我脸色看吧?
So you're playing the boss now, huh?
你应该知道警队机密档案是不可以随便泄露
You damn well know the files are classified.
我把你当兄弟 你跟我说这个?
I treat you like a bro. Is this what I get?
你当我是兄弟就不要问
If you're a real bro, stop asking!
没事吧
It's okay.
冷静点
Calm down.
慢慢说嘛
Don't lose your head.
她把孩子打掉了
She had an abortion!
那有什么 生孩子嘛
It's no big deal. Just a baby.
打掉了再生一个嘛 就是这样的 有什么呢!
You can always have another one! That's life!
我和你一起四年了
I've been with you for four years.
去警局保你也有十几次
And I've bailed you out tons of times.
跟我家人吃顿饭...
One minute we're dining with my folks...
都可以突然跑去砍人
...the next you'll be in a gang fight
我不想孩子将来也是这样
I don't want our baby to grow up like you.
你明不明白?
Don't you understand?
见到我这么拘谨?
Why so uptight?
没有
No, nothing.
听三叔说 你干得不错
Uncle John says you're doing well.
有没有想过回家里来帮忙?
Ever thought about helping the family out?
我知道你不想让人知道 你跟倪家的关系
I know you want to keep a distance from the Ngai's
但我们是亲兄弟 这是事实 没的改变
But we're blood brothers. It's a fact.
对吧
Right?
这个星期天我女儿生日
It's my daughter's birthday this Sunday.
我想你回家坐一坐
You're invited.
你真的不喜欢跟我说话?
You really hate talking to me, huh?
不是
No.
No
没多久就升职 很快就升警司了?
Promoted already? Soon you'll be a superintendent.
你全职当警察好了
Might as well become a full-time cop.
琛哥跟你开玩笑呢 快笑一笑
Sam's kidding. Go ahead, give me a smile.
这两年全靠琛哥给我情报
Thanks for your intel these couple years.
以前你是小角色 叫你抓些小鱼小虾米
When you were still a rookie,
顺便帮我扫扫那些牛鬼蛇神
I helped you catch some small potatoes.
现在你升了职 要抓就要抓些高级的喽
It's about time you caught some big shots.
干脆你来抓我好喽
How about catching me?
哇 怎么这么脏啊你?要不就抓个美女
Isn't that cute? Or you can catch hot chicks.
哎呀!要死
What are you doing?!
哪有这么漂亮的女人?
What a hot hootchie mama!
你男人一定很帅的 不然怎么配得上你?
Your man must be one good-looking bastard.
那不就是你嘛
It's you! Who else?
- 走了! - 又走?
- Gotta go. - Already?
约了倪先生 要干活嘛!
Gotta go meet Mr. Ngai.
琛哥...对你真好
Sam's so good to you .
可惜他对自己不好
But he's not good to himself.
四年了
It's been four years.
本来他可以做老大
He could be in charge now.
但是他全都给了姓倪的
But he gave everything to the Ngai's.
现在没人敢碰姓倪的
Now the Ngai Family's all big and bad
那件事 阿孝一定找人算账
Hau must've figured it out.
这四年来
For the past four years,
我一直都睡不好
I haven't been sleeping well.
我是黄志诚总督察
Hello. I' m Inspector Wong Chi-Shing.
放心吧 玛莉姐
Don't worry, Mary.
我不会让你出事的
I won't let anything happen to you .
你说话要算话哦
Words, words, words.
一定
I promise.
扔个球来看看
Toss it up.
前两天 有个地产经纪来看房子
Two days ago, a real estate agent came.
你们猜他开什么价?
Guess how much he offered?
一亿六 一亿六千万
160 million. 160 million!
你们说香港搞什么?
What's wrong with Hong Kong? Tell me!
我记得爸爸买这儿的时候是...
When my dad bought it,
九百...二十八万
it was 9 million...280 thousand.
现在这什么世界?
What a world!
倪先生 要换房子吗?
Trading up, Mr. Ngai?
没什么 九七了 移民
1997 is approaching. Time to emigrate.
那有什么大不了的?
No big deal.
现在一切都很方便
Communication's easy these days.
有事打个电话回来就行了
We're just a phone call away.
我也是这么想 但是又怕交不起电话费
I'm just worried about the phone bill.
你们知道 电话公司都狠的
The phone company's greedy, you know.
其实我和妈妈商量过
I've discussed it with Mom.
现在我们倪家的生意 都已经上了轨道
Our businesses are on the right track.
你们也帮我们打理生意不少日子了
You guys helped out so much in the past.
我们不想让人觉得我们打完了斋不要和尚
I don't want to be ungrateful.
所以打算走了以后 把这盘生意...
I want to split the business up...
全分给你们几位
...among you guys
当是感谢也好 公积金也好 对吧
Treat it as a gift or a retirement fund.
吃啊 喜欢吃什么就拿什么
Let's eat! Take whatever you want!
以后大家有空多聚聚 就像今天这样 挺好
We should hang out like this more often.
倪先生
Mr. Ngai.
你真要走?
Are you leaving for real?
你走了会乱的
After you're gone, hell will break loose!
阿琛 你信佛的吧?
You're a Buddhist, aren't you, Sam?
"拿起容易 放下难"
"Easy to start. Hard to let go."
我今天放得下 你该替我高兴
I'm letting go. Be happy for me.
我替你想过
I've thought about it.
以后一定是可卡因的世界
Cocaine will be the future.
他们四个从南美一小包一小包的运过来
Those four ship it in small bags from South America.
成不了什么气候
Small-timers!
我和泰国那边呢 已经谈好了
I've closed a deal with the Thais.
以后让你独家进口
You'll have a monopoly.
到时候你是大庄家 谁都听你的
You 'll be the top dog. Leader of the pack.
过两天你去泰国办好了事情 就可以回来开始
Go to Thailand and wrap up the logistics.
你打算收拾他们四个?
You plan to get rid of those four?
右边的靠近一点啊
Move closer to the center, please.
永仁
Yan.
过来一家人拍张照
Come join the family portrait.
来...站这儿
Stand next to me!
好 看镜头 一 二 三
One more shot. Okay. One, two, three.
好 再来一张
One more!
其实这两年我很少留在香港
I haven't been around much these past two years.
所以今天...
So today...
难得一家人...共聚天伦
...It's rare to spend time...with the whole family like this
姐姐 哥哥和弟弟都做了正行
Your siblings are in legitimate businesses.
所以觉得你应该回家帮忙
It's time you helped out the family.
以前爸爸做每件事都是为了这个家
Everything Dad did was for the family.
我也是
I did the same.
我希望你也是
Hope you will, too.
下个星期有笔买卖 我想你跟我一起去
A deal's coming up next week. Come with me.
到时候我找你
I'll call you.
这个交易很重要 所以他要亲自去
I think he's taking the deal seriously.
日期下个礼拜三 十四号
He'll go in person next Wednesday.
十四号 倪坤的死忌
The 14th... Kwun's memorial.
他想收拾那四个老大
Hau wants to whack the Big Four.
你知道他为什么把韩琛支开?
Why does he send Sam away?
不知道 便是韩琛应该能帮他的忙
Don't know. Sam should be of help to him.
他连韩琛也想除掉
Unless he wants to kill Sam also!
我跟了你好几天了
I've been following you around for days.
不管怎么说 我也是你们上司
I'm your superior after all
我想知道你们下一步想干什么
I want to know what your plan is
姓倪的是你的家人
The Ngai's are your family
你知道现在你在做什么吗?
Do you really know what you're doing?
长官
Sir!
我是警察
I'm a cop!
好
Good.
敬个礼给我看看
Give me a salute.
订了位子跟你吃饭 一会儿有空?
I've booked a table. Care for dinner?
我戴帽子好看吗?
Do I look cool in my cap?
傻强
Keung.
怎么样
Looking good?
穿成这样 到泰国搞什么?
What'll you do in Thailand in that outfit?
不搞什么
Have some shark fin soup.
吃鱼翅 按摩 再来个一王二后
A massage. Get two whores for a threesome.
还用说?
That's for sure.
老公
Honey!
怎么样?
What?
去泰国怎么不告诉我呢?
Why didn't you tell me about your trip?
去办事嘛 你以为打泰拳啊?
It's a business trip! Not for fun!
放心吧 不会乱搞 啊!
Don't worry. I'll behave.
倪永孝要收拾国华他们
Hau plans to whack Wah and those guys.
我知道
I know.
那你知不知道他也想干掉你?
But did you know you 're his target too?
别听人乱说 怎么会呢?
Nonsense! How can that be?
总之你别管 在机场等我 就这样
Just wait for me at the airport!
琛哥 该登机了
Time to board, Sam!
我能做的就这么多
That's all I can do for now.
等阿琛下飞机再打给他
Call Sam again when the plane lands.
我今天晚上就要杀了阿孝
I'm going to kill Hau tonight.
你别乱来
Don't do anything rash.
我不是乱来
I'm not being rash.
我只记得四年前
Four years ago...
是你叫我杀掉倪坤的
...you told me to kill Kwun.
你什么意思?要挟我?
So what? Want to blackmail me now?
我不是要挟你
I'm not blackmailing you .
而是我们两个现在 都不能回头了
We simply passed the point of no return!
到时候我调走所有人
I'll send everybody away then.
今天晚上的行动要绝对保密
Tonight's operation's top secret
我们分三个组
We're divided into three teams.
A组 把住这个出口
Team A watches here.
B组 这个出口
Team B here.
没我的命令不准行动
Wait for my order before doing anything.
C组一直跟着目标人物 直到...
Team C follows the target until...
改了日期不通知我?
Nobody told me about the date change!
我早就说过 阿孝这个人很难捉摸
You know Hau changes his mind all the time.
你以为只有你在他身边有人?
You think Yan's the only mole?
我那个卧底跟着他七年了
My man's been undercover for seven years!
那副牌呢?
Where's the deck of cards?
今天晚上 我们一起决定
It's a tie. We'll run the show together tonight. Deal?
出发
Let's go!
嗨
Hi
- 你好吗? - 很好 谢谢
- How are you? - Fine. thank you.
别动...都站好
Freeze! Freeze! Hold it right there!
阿孝
What's up, Hau?
你非要等律师来才开口?
Zipping it till your lawyer gets here?
合作点吧
Come on, cooperate with us!
别这么说 我谢谢你合作才对
In fact, I appreciate your cooperation.
倪先生 你说话这么深奥
Are you speaking Zen, Mr. Ngai?
没人明白的
I don't get it.
爸爸常说
Dad used to say...
出来跑 无论做过什么...
... the way things work in the streets...
迟早要还
... what goes around always comes around.
他死了四年 今天是时候了
He died four years ago. It's about time.
老板 可以了
The stove's hot enough now.
放下吧
put down
老板 来了
She's here, boss.
过来呀
Come here
师兄 走了
partner,I'm going.
你人在这儿
You 're here now.
还能出什么花样?
What can you swing?
别着急 等着瞧
Wait and see
长官 查到了
Got it! Sir
那两个老外是私家侦探
the two foreigners are private eyes.
喂 老公 你在哪里?
Honey! Where are you?
我在泰国的嘛
Thailand, of course.
你快点回来
Come back right away!
神经病!我回来干什么?
Are you nuts? Why should I come back?
你别管那么多 你快点回来
Don't ask questions! Just come back!
阿孝要找人杀你
Hau wants you dead!
胡说 我正帮他做事啊
Nonsense! I'm working for him as we speak!
你听我说
Listen to me!
倪坤...是我杀的
I'm the one who killed Kwun.
有没有录象机?
You've got a VCR?
好看吗?
Isn't it good?
非常精彩
What an awesome show!
聪明点 有事就走
Take care. Run if you have to
阿孝有什么说的?
What did Hau say?
- 阿琛 - 辛尼
- Sam. - Sunny!
倪先生他让我好好的招待你
Mr. Ngai told me to take good care of you!
我只是记得四年前...
Four years ago...
是你叫我杀掉倪坤的
...you told me to kill Kwun .
你什么意思?要挟我?
So what? Want to blackmail me now?
我不是要挟你
I'm not blackmailing you .
而是我们现两个现在 都不能回头了
We simply passed the point of no return
到时候我调走所有人
I'll send everybody away then .
阿伦和钟逊
I hired Alan and Johnson...
是我特地请来帮我查 杀我爸爸的凶手
...to investigate my father's murder
想不到你们有些警务人员...
Who would've known? The police conspired...
知法犯法
to murder my father.
杀害我爸爸这样的良好市民
A law-abiding citizen.
陆长官
SP Luk
画面里那个 算不算警察?
Isn't that an officer in the video?
怎么样做 抓不抓他...
Whether to nail him or not...
你自己决定
...that's up to you
真的很好看
What a good show!
你很上镜
You're so friggin' photogenic.
四年前
Four years ago...
你们收了韩琛的女人多少钱?
How much did Sam's woman pay you?
倪先生 给次机会吧
Give me another chance, Mr. Ngai.
四年前 我给过他们机会
I gave them a chance four years ago.
他们没要
They didn't take it.
如果今天我给你机会
If I give you a chance...
你要不要?
Are you going to take it today?
你来了我们倪家七年
You've been with us for seven years now.
你是警察
You're a cop.
我们是黑社会
We're the bad guys.
所以各安天命
Time to accept our fates.
你不要怪我
You can't blame me.
因为你们的黄长官杀了我爸爸
Your Inspector Wong killed my dad.
有没有琛哥的消息?
Any words from Sam?
琛哥联络过我
Sam called me.
他说他没事
He said he was fine.
叫你在这儿躲几天 等他回来
He asked you to wait for him here.
你的家人呢?
Where are your folks?
都移民了
All emigrated.
你怎么不去?
You didn't go with them?
琛哥快走!泰国人没追来
Let's go, Sam! We got rid of the Thais
快走啊
Let's go!
你知道你走不了的
You know you're not going to make it.
我知道
I know.
我女人在香港很危险
My girl's in danger in Hong Kong too.
我求你帮帮我
Please help me.
我为什么要帮你?
Why should I?
因为我帮你除掉你老大
'Cause I'll help you whack your boss.
我知道你很想坐那个位子
I know you want to be in charge.
还有
Moreover...
我一直当你是我的好朋友
I've been treating you as a pal.
别信他!琛哥 别信他
Don't believe him, Sam! Don't!
走开
Get lost!
- 别信他 - 走开
- Don't believe him! - Get lost!
对不起 琛哥
Sorry, Sam.
来抓我?
Are you here to arrest me?
你现在要去杀阿孝
If you're going to kill Hau,
我就抓你
I will.
那就是没商量了
Then there's nothing to talk about.
我跟上头已经说好了
I spoke with my superiors.
他们说这一次 一定支持你
They're with you all the way this time.
怎样支持?
How?
我教唆杀人呀
I conspired in murder!
就连上面那些老外都说
Even the Brits agree that...
不可以让黑社会胡来
...we can't let the triads break us
全警局的人都支持你
The whole department's behind you.
你说够不够招?
Good enough?
你的牌呢?
Where's your deck of cards?
这次我们比大
The higher points win
听我的 跟我回警局开会
I'm calling the shots. Come back with me to the department.
钥匙
The key!
算了 我已经够糗的了
Forget it. I screwed up.
别连累人家了
No need to drag everyone down with me.
这是我们第一次合作抓老千
We found this deck on our first outing together.
你留下来的
You've been keeping it all this time.
我一直都知道
I knew that all along.
这么多年 我听了你好几次
I've let you get your way in the past.
也该听我一次了吧
It's your turn to listen for once.
我说过我们是兄弟
We're like brothers.
你有事我能不管吗?
Think I'm just gonna be a spectator?
罗继是我安插进去的卧底
Law's my snitch in the Ngai Family.
已经好几天没跟我联络了
He hasn't contacted me for days.
阿仁也是
Neither has Yan.
钥匙
The key!
出来呀
Help!
帮忙啊
Help! Get some help!
为什么?
Why?Why?
你为什么骗我?
Why did you lie to me?
没有啊
I didn't!
琛哥出事了
Something happened to Sam!
我跟你说过 我是个很简单的女人
I told you I was a simple woman.
现在我老公出事了 我怎么也得做点事情
I have to do something for my husband.
我要去泰国
I'm going to Thailand.
你不去行不行?
Please don't go!
算了 你就当没有跟过我们
Forget it! You don't have to follow us anymore
我是说 我叫你别去行不行?
I mean, I don't want you to go.
其实 你跟琛哥那么多年
You've been with Sam for years...
有没有想过
Has it occurred to you...
琛哥已经死了
Maybe Sam's dead!
你说什么?
What did you say?
我可以照顾你
I can take care of you.
你干什么?
What are you doing?
我不想你走
I don't want you to go.
你造反啊你?
You're out of line!
我告诉你
Listen up!
我是你老大的女人
I'm your boss's woman!
以后别再让我见到你
Don't let me see your face again!
今晚她会去机场
She will go to the airport tonight...
喂?喂?
Hello? Hello?
倪坤 是我杀的
I'm the one who killed Kwun.
只要男人好
Aman treats me well.
我做什么都行
I'd do anything.
(时间)
(Time)
(1997年)
(Year: 1997)
档案编号IO3142
File number IO3142
有关黄志诚督察教唆谋杀案
About Inspector Wong conspiring in murder.
现由三位高级警官 作第十一次内部聆讯
This is the 11 th internal hearing.
黄志诚督察
Inspector Wong,
你有没有问题?
do you have any questions?
没有...
No...
没有
No.
身为督察 必须具备领导才能
An inspector should possess leadership skills
刘警官
Mr. Lau
你现为普通警员
you joined as a police constable
能不能告诉评选会
Could you tell the promotion board
提升你为督察的理由呢?
why you deserve to be promoted?
当然可以
Of course
一九九五年四月十一日
On April 11, 1995,
投诉科收到这盒带子
The department received this tape
指控你串谋黑帮 合谋杀人
accusing you of conspiring with the triads in a murder.
我认罪 长官
I confess, sir.
现在是一九九七年了
It's already 1997
七月一号之前
If we don't receive your PO assessment report
如果我们还没有收到你的评审报告
Before the 1st of July
你认为还可以获得晋升吗?
Do you still think you can be promoted?
中国人有句话
In Chinese, there is a saying
那就是 一朝天子一朝臣
With a new king come new followers
所以 我认为到那个时候我要重新开始
So, I guess we will have to start all over again
你为什么会变成这样?
What happened to you?
如果我告诉你
If I told you...
这些所谓的证据全都不成立
...that the evidence couldn't stand...
你想不想重新再来?
...would you like to start over?
对不起 我犯了法
I'm sorry. I broke the law.
你对九七以后警队的士气有什么看法?
What do you think of the police force's morale after 1997?
中国人注重感情
Chinese people are sentimental
我也希望法律能继续支持我
I hope the law will continue to back me up
但是 我同样坚信自己的能力 长官
But, I strongly believe in myself, sir!
各位怎样对我 我知道
I'm grateful to all of you.
但我没有信心 我已经输了
But I've got no confidence left. I lost!
那阿昌又怎样?
What about Luk then?
你觉得现在这么做 对得起阿昌吗?
Can you face him if you give up now?
阿黄 这场仗还没打完
The war's not over.
我们每个人 都希望对这件事有个交待
We all want a closure to this incident.
我们想外面知道 香港不是由姓倪的来管
Hong Kong is not run by the Ngai Family.
这里有一份国际刑警档案
Here's a file from the Interpol.
你看完了再作决定
Read it before your make up your mind.
有没有参加过泰国的丧礼?
Ever been to a funeral in Thailand?
几个月前
A few months ago...
我为老婆办了一个
I had one for my wife.
请了些大师 给她念了三天的经
The monks chanted for three full days.
这三天 我没流过一滴眼泪
During those three days, I didn't shed a single tear.
没想到出殡那天
On the day of the burial...
那些苦力 把棺材抬到厅里
...they left the casket in the living room.
当时我很生气
I was mad.
很想打人
I wanted to beat them up.
但大师就对我说
The monk told me...
这是他们的习俗
...it's a tradition in Thailand.
死的人
The deceased...
只要我们能够陪她
...as long as we keep her company...
过一段时间
...for a little while longer...
她就可以安息了
...she can attain eternal peace.
但是我对大师说
But I asked the monk...
我老婆不在棺材里
...what if my wife was not in the coffin?
她可不可以安息呀?
Could she still attain eternal peace?
嫂子的事 对不起
Sorry about your wife.
大师马上按住我这里
The monk placed his hand here.
他说 "没问题
He said, "No problem,
你太太在你这儿就行喽"
Your wife's here."
而碰巧这里
And here's exactly...
就是泰国人打我一枪的地方
...where the Thais shot me!
我立刻对自己说
So I told myself,
我是不可能再回头了
I've passed the point of no return.
这次回香港指证倪永孝 很危险
Testifying against Hau in Hong Kong could be dangerous.
你这么帅 我有信心
I believe in you . You 're so handsome.
很久没人跟我说这句话了 谢谢
Haven't heard that for ages. Thanks.
你有什么打算?
What's your plan?
尽力而为吧
Just trying to do my best.
没什么 工作嘛
No big deal. It's my job.
搞定这件事之后 我会离开香港
I'll leave Hong Kong when it's all over.
阿黄
Hey,you!
你变了
You've changed.
宝宝
Baby!
货里掺东西了?
You diluted the coke, didn't you?
没话说了?
Got anything to say?
全给我吸了它
Take it all then.
阿仁 别那么绝
Don't go too far, Yan.
让小的看见 哪有心情做事啊?
It'd break the boys' morale.
倪先生叫我这么做的
Mr. Ngai asked me to be in charge here.
不喜欢就送他上医院
Don't like it? Drive him to the hospital!
无论他们做错什么
No matter what,
他们始终是长辈
they're elders after all.
你以后还有很多东西要跟他们学
You 've got lots to learn from them.
三叔再做几年就退休了
Uncle John will retire in a few years.
你明白我的意思吧?
You know what I mean?
我不想在这个时候 有什么事情发生
I don't need any hiccups now.
今晚劳工体育会请吃回归宴
The Labor Athletic Association is hosting a dinner reception...
我们所有的政协候选人都会去
...for us Political Consultative candidates.
如果这次我成功
If everything works out,
我们倪家以后就能抬起头来做人
our family will no longer live in the shadows.
张先生
Mr. Cheung.
- 倪先生 - 总会主席
- Mr. Ngai - Chairman
- 你好 - 你好...
- How are you? - Good. Good
我听洪大律师提起过你呀
When Solicitor Hung mentioned you,
我还不大相信呢
I didn't believe him.
倪先生 你看看你 你真是年青有为啊
You 're amazingly young, Mr. Ngai.
属啥的?
What's your Zodiac sign?
牛
Ox.
属牛
The Year of the Ox.
属牛好啊
Ox is good.
陈主任最喜欢跟年轻人打交道
Director Chan likes young people.
- 待会儿给你介绍介绍 - 谢谢
- I'll introduce you later. - Thanks.
是吗?
Really?
主任对我说过 他是最痛恨黑社会的
Director Chan said he hated the triads.
对了 梁长官
That's right, SP Leung
倪先生刚接受邀请 到警察投诉部当顾问
Mr. Ngai's been invited to consult with the police.
是吗?恭喜恭喜呀
Really? Congratulations!
老陈 最近到哪里打球?
Where do you golf these days, Chan?
中山
Zhong Shan Onsen
中山?你现在打多少杆哪?
Zhong Shan? What's your handicap these days?
你好你好 小姓倪
How are you? My name's Ngai...
倪永孝先生
Mr. Ngai Wing-Hau.
我是倪先生律师
I'm Mr. Ngai's solicitor.
今天是劳工体育会的回归酒会
Tonight's a celebration for HK's hand-over.
有什么事 酒会之后再说行吗?
All other business can wait.
我说不行
What if I say no?
有没有问题?
Got any problem with that?
倪先生
Mr. Ngai,
现在怀疑你
You're a suspect
和一九九五年多宗谋杀案有关
in several murder cases in 1995.
这张是拘捕令
You're under arrest
现在要拘捕你
This is your arrest warrant
你所说的话
Everything you say
我们会用纸和笔记下
will be recorded...
将来作为呈堂证供
and could be used as evidence against you.
有没有问题?
Do you have any questions?
没有
No.
我看过他们的资料
I looked through their files.
谋杀罪名一定不成立
The murder charges won't stand.
不过 身为三合会的龙头
But your being a triad boss...
我无法帮你脱罪
That one will stick.
三哥 刚才几个工会和政党打电话来
The unions and the political parties called.
说想收回他们回归晚会的贴子
They want to withdraw their invitations.
港奥办来消息
Words from the HK and Macau Affairs Office
你候选人的资格被取消了
They have revoked your candidacy.
打电话去北京 找些朋友帮忙
Call Beijing. Get some friends to help.
我试试看
Let me try.
算了
Forget it.
他们连个死了的人都能找到
They even found a dead man to testify against you.
所有人都知道 韩琛对倪家忠心耿耿
Everyone knows how loyal Sam was to you.
他做污点证人 这官司怎么打?
Now he's a prosecution witness. It's over.
对不起 我帮不了你
Sorry. Can't help you.
那时候 你说可以顺利过渡
You said there'd be no problem.
大家都看好我们倪家
Everyone's watching how we will react.
现在怎么办?
What're you going to do?
你要我怎么办?
What can I do?
恐吓中国政府啊?
Threaten the Chinese government?
他不是这个意思
Don't take it the wrong way.
只不过大家同坐一条船
We're all in the same boat.
那我下船了
Time for me to get off then
我是你们的律师 不是你们的人
I'm just a lawyer. Not one of you.
我不想跟你们沉船 对不起
I don't intend to sink with you . Sorry.
是
Yes.
查到韩琛有个老婆和女儿在泰国
Sam has a wife and daughter in Thailand.
怎么做你看着办
It's your call.
姐
Sis.
我想你和大哥 弟弟陪妈妈
You and the brothers should take mom...
去夏威夷那边住一段时间
... and go to Hawaii for a while.
好吧
Yes.
也好 反正我们很久没过去了
Okay. Haven't been there for a while.
你会不会有事?
Are you going to be all right?
没事...
I'll be fine.
对不起 我帮不上家里什么忙
Sorry I can't help the family.
最要紧你没事
The key thing now is you turn out okay.
别这么说 一家人嘛
Don't be silly. We're a family.
照顾妈妈
Take care of mom!
放心 交给我们三个
Don't worry. Leave it to us three.
我总觉得 就算我出庭作证
Even with my testimony,
阿孝顶多坐几年牢而已
Hau will only get a couple years.
那倒是
It's true.
如果要他终身监禁 除非他杀了你
He'll have to whack you to get life.
- 我走了 - 阿黄
- I Gotta go - Hey, you
这次真的谢谢你
I have to thank you.
没有你
Without you
我也回不了香港
I could never have come back to Hong Kong.
不跟你说了 我最近很忙
Save it! I'm busy these days.
你有什么需要 就跟他们说
Anything you need, ask them.
这组人负责保护你
They'll protect you.
行!
I know.
琛哥
Sam.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么样 好吗?
So, how's it going?
还好 调到刑事情报科
Good. Been transferred to the ClB.
下个月升做见习督察
I'll be an Inspector-in-Training next month.
玛莉姐走的时候
Did Mary call you...
有没有找过你?
...before she left?
琛哥 节哀顺变
Don't be too hard on yourself, Sam.
黄长官说 有什么事可以找你
Inspector Wong said to find you if I needed anything.
你是不是真的会帮我?
Will you really help me?
我以为你不会来
I thought you wouldn't come.
为什么我不会来?
Why's that?
怎么样?
So here we are.
两年了
It's been two years.
因为有份杀我爸爸
Because of my father's case,
所以两年都不敢找我?
you didn't dare to call me for two years?
不敢跟我说话?
You couldn't face me?
是
Right.
保险箱里 是倪家这两年的犯罪证据
All you need to nail Hau is in the safe.
我排好档案和日期了
I've organized the files according to date.
为什么还肯帮我?
Why do you still help me?
我不是想帮你
I'm not helping you.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
我答应过陆长官的事 我要做到
I want to keep my promises to SP Luk!
我不想再做卧底了
And I don't want to be a mole anymore.
再做两年 我就成尖沙嘴老大了
Two more years and I'll become the top dog in Tsim Sha Tsui.
怎么办?想坐牢啊?
What for? To end up in prison?
以前的事我忘了
Let's bury the past.
总之拜托你赶快办完这件事 调我回警署
Just finish up my case and bring me back into the department.
给我一个平平稳稳的位子
Give me a decent desk.
要对着海
Make sure it has a sea view.
但是别再让我再见到你
And don't let me see your face again.
放心吧
Don't worry.
你不会见到我
You won't see me anymore.
还有
One more thing.
档案里有些字我不会写
I couldn't spell some of the words.
你看不懂就来找我
Come find me if you don't understand.
但千万别调乱了次序 我排了很久
But don't mess up the order.
调乱了 我宰了你
I'll kill you if you mess that up.
那就好了 债可以还清了
That's great. Put me out of misery.
想得美
You wish.
谢谢警官
Thank you, Officer.
阿琛 资料齐了 律政司批示三天后上庭
Sum, we're all set. The trial will start in three days.
韩先生
Mr. Han
重案组
Hello, OCTB!
黄长官 证人不见了
Inspector Wong! Sam's gone!
韩琛应该是从厨房通道跑掉的
He escaped through the kitchen.
谁把守厨房通道?
Who was guarding the kitchen?
对不起 长官
Sorry, sir.
黄长官 韩琛走之前
Officer Wong, Sam'd made a call to Thailand...
打了个电话回泰国
...before he escaped
喂
Hello?
倪先生
Mr. Ngai.
找我什么事啊?
What do you want from me?
是你打话给我的
You called me.
所以应该你告诉我 能帮我什么忙
So tell me how you can help me.
对吧?坐
Am I right? Sit down.
杀我吧
Kill me.
杀了我就天下太平了
Kill me and it's all over.
我为什么要杀你?
Why should I?
我没干这种事很久了
Haven't done that kind of stuff for ages.
有什么话 可以坐下来慢慢商量
Everything can be negotiated, Sam.
香港这么大
Hong Kong's big enough for us both, Sam.
你愿意的话 我们可以一起合作
We can even be partners.
以前的事算了
Let's forget about the past.
你一定会杀我
You will kill me.
今晚你就会杀我
You 'll kill me tonight.
我杀了你 你老婆和女儿怎么办?
But who's gonna take care of your family?
刚刚收到消息
Just in!
倪永孝抓了韩琛在泰国的老婆和女儿
Hau has Sam's wife and daughter as hostages.
那是他泰国的佣人
That's his Thai maid.
这几年 我死不了
I managed to stay alive all these years.
是因为
It's all because...
我有帮个很好的泰国朋友
... I have some good buddies in Thailand
你也听听这个电话
You want to take this call.
打去夏威夷的
It's from Hawaii.
你全家都在那儿
Your whole family's there.
包括我泰国的朋友
My Thai buddies, too.
你好 倪先生
Hey, Mr. Ngai.
我老大吩咐我
My boss asked me
叫我好好的照顾你家人
to take good care of your family
爸爸!爸爸在哪儿?
Daddy! Where are you?
倪先生
Mr. Ngai!
闭嘴
Shut up!
我说了你今晚会杀我的喽
You 'll whack me tonight. I told you so.
警察!别动!
Police!Freeze!Freeze!
倪永孝 放下枪
Put it down, Ngai Wing-Hau!
由着他吧
Let him!
他以前杀过我
He tried to kill me once before.
就让他再杀一次吧
Let him do it again!
各位警官
Officers!
等会儿他打死我
After he shoots me...
开不开枪就随便你们啦
...it'll be your call to shoot him or not!
出来跑 迟早要还的
What goes around comes around!
两个问题
Two questions.
你有没有杀光他全家?
Did you kill his whole family?
当然没有
Of course not!
我和泰国朋友 吓唬他呢!
My Thai buddies and I were just bluffing.
你早就料到我会帮你杀他?
Did you expect me to kill him for you?
我说没有 你相信吗?
Would you believe me if I said no?
我准备好死在这里的
I expected to die here!
我只有这个办法
It was my only way.
对不起
Sorry.
你知不知道我用了多少时间
Did you know how hard I worked...
我搜集了多少证据
...to collect tons of evidence...
足够让他坐一辈子牢
...to put him away for life?
喂 哪位?
Who's this?
找琛哥?
How are you?
琛哥 泰国人
The Thai guy, Sam.
保罗
Paul!
谢谢
Thank you.
那就好了
Everything went according to plan.
以后我们合作
We're now partners.
货直接卖到香港
The cocaine will ship straight to HK without any middlemen from now on.
倪家的事 要不要我来摆平啊?
Should I take care of the rest of the Ngai Family?
保罗
Paul...
我想 别做得的太绝了吧!
Maybe we shouldn't go too far.
之前你碰上我
It was destiny that you bumped into me.
算你捡回了条命
Otherwise you would've been killed.
那枪没打死你
We were destined to be partners
我们就是拍档
when my gun failed to kill you .
- 就要做得那么绝 - 好!
- Forget you ever knew the meaning of "too far. " - OK
在会展新翼进行的中英交接仪式
The hand-over ceremony of Hong Kong
在较早前十一时二十分正式开始
commenced earller at 11:20.
两国军乐团也已经奏出不同的乐章
Both countries' anthems were played.
同时一面英国国旗
A British flag
早在会场里面冉冉飘起
rose up in the hall .
仪式虽然庄严
The ceremony was dignified.
但是在开始前
Yet it'd its share of relaxed moments
气氛却非常和谐
before its commencement.
在双方军乐团演奏的时候
When both countries' marching bands played.
中方代表团的成员正在拍照留念
some Chinese representatives took pictures.
而查尔斯王子
Prince Charles
和港督彭定康到场时也展露微笑
and Governor Patten were smiling.
仪式正式开始
As the ceremony officially commenced...
三名英军
...three British soldiers
和三名手持中国国旗的解放军
and three Chinese ones
慢慢的步上主礼台
marched slowly onto the podium .
三名解放军
The Chinese soldiers
向中方主礼人展示中国国旗
displayed the PRC flag.
随后
Following their lead.
三名香港皇家警察
three HK Royal Pollce officers
和三名手持特区区旗的
...emerged with
特区警察步上礼台
three HK SAR Police officers
三名特区警察 向中方主礼嘉宾
The three SAR officers displayed
展示香港特区区旗
the HK SAR flag to the honorable guests.
与此同时
And now.
全场观礼的嘉宾 都已经纷纷起立
all the guests have risen .
当时间到达七月一日
It was exactly midnight.
零时零分之际
The arrival of July 1. 1997.
中国国旗
The PRC flag rose up
以及香港特区区旗 徐徐升起
with the HK SAR flag...
见证着一个殖民地统治的结束
...marking the end of the colonial era.
同时也为历史上
It also signified the beginning
一国两制的管治揭开了序幕
of the "One Country. Two Systems" pollcy.
中华人民共和国
The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
香港特别行政区正式成立
of the People 's Republic of China has been establlshed.
没什么的 已经定了
Okay. It's a deal.
过来跟我
Come join me.
跟老大最怕什么 你知道吗?
You know what kind of boss is the worst?
跟着个不象样的就完了
The ugly boss.
样子很重要 你看我一脸油
Look's everything! Look how I shine!
小姐 叫什么名字?
What's your name, miss?
我失恋了 我叫玛莉...
I'm Ma... Mary.
M-A...
M-A-Y...
M-A-R-Y
M-A-R-Y.
Mary
Mary.
无间有三
Continuous Hell embodies 3 components:
时无间 空无间 受者无间
Uninterrupted Time, Unlimited Space, Boundless Suffering.
犯五逆界者 永堕此狱
Transgressors of the Five Deadly Sins fall into this hell forever,
尽受终极之无间
condemned to the ultimate incessant suffering.